BU Records: Erisophian Literary Society, Inclusive: 1853-1961, undated, Bulk: 1872-1928
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Administrative Records, 1853-1961, undated; 1
  - Library Circulation, 1879-1902, undated; 3
    - Library Records, 1891-1893 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Library Catalog, 1893-1900 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Library Records, 1898 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Library Records, 1900-1901 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Library Records, 1901-1902 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Library Records, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Circulation Cards, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Legal Records, 1897; 4
    - Charter from the State of Texas, 1897 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Literary Productions, 1860-1914, undated; 2
  This series contains volumes of the Erisophian Literary Journal, including parts of the original series that began in Independence, Texas, and the “new series” that began after the 1872 reformation of the society in Waco, Texas. All members of the society were required to contribute to the journal and often submitted works using pseudonyms. In addition to the Erisophian Literary Journal, several speeches and essays written by members are included. Programs provide insight regarding the debate topics and entertainment at the events hosted by the society and in conjunction with the Rufus C. Burleson Literary Society. Many of the pamphlets provide a brief history of the organization and include the society’s constitution and by-laws. The pamphlets were primarily made for distribution among potential members of the society. Also included in the series are various clippings and ephemera such as business cards, stationary, checks, and blank forms. This series is in poor condition.
  - Erisophian Literary Journal, 1860-1880, undated; 1
    - Volume 3, Number 10 - Farewell, 1860-1864 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Volume 1, Number 1 - Volume 2, Number 6, 1872-1874 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Volume 3, Number 1 - Volume 5, Number 2, 1874-1876 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Volume 5, Number 3 - Volume 8, Number 3, 1887-1880 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Volume 8, Number 4; Volume 10, Number 5; list of authors and pseudonyms, 1880, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Speeches, undated; 2
    - Speeches, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Essays, undated; 3
    - Thomas Stalworth Henderson essays, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1884-1914, undated; 4
    - Event Programs, 1884-1914, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets, 1896-1913; 5
    - Pamphlets, 1896-1913 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, undated; 6
    - Newspaper Clippings and Broadsides, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Printed Materials, undated; 7
    - Blank Forms and Ephemera, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1883-1927, undated; 3
  This series contains correspondence to and from university faculty, university departments, the Rufus C. Burleson Society, debate organizers, prospective speakers, and former members. Some pieces of correspondence contain handwritten notes. This series is in average condition.
  - Correspondence, 1883-1927, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)